A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants Them-Tw FA732H FA732H
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Grants Them-Tw
1936-2006
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA732H
33.42 Cubic Feet 2905 16mm microfilm reels, 437 35mm microfilm reels
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement note
Each Ford Foundation Grant and the corresponding Grant File is identified by a unique Program Action (PA) number. PA numbers begin with the year a grant was made (2-digits), followed by a sequential number within that year (4-digits).
For example: PA 55-0123 was the 123rd grant made in the year 1955. PA numbers are often typed or handwritten on Ford documents in the following format: 55-123 (year)-(####). However, the Ford Foundation's grants database (LINKS) uses an 8-digit format for PA numbers: 05500123 (0YY#####).
Beginning in the 1970s the 4th digit in the 8-digit PA number was used to encode at least three different types of Ford grants:
0YY5#### = Delegated Authority Grants (DAG) / Delegated Authority Projects (DAP)
0YY6#### = Grants to Individuals
0YY9#### = Foundation Administered Projects (FAP)
After the year 2000 a "1" is used as the first digit in the 8-digit PA number to signify the 21st century. For example the 123rd grant made in 2012 would be PA number 11200123.
Grant Files were not microfilmed in numerical order, and the Ford Foundation's LINKS database must be used to identify on which microfilm reel (or reels) any specific Grant File is housed.
Other Finding Aids note
Grant Files are indexed in the Ford Foundation's grants database (LINKS). This database is not available to the public. The Ford Foundation Central Index cards, 1950-1996 (FA736) also provide indexing for Grant Files, and can be searched by institutional/organizational name, personal name, grant location, and subject. Grant Files from 1953 to 1974 are also listed by PA number in the Fund File Index.
Arrangement note
Each Ford Foundation Grant File is arranged into 4 sections:
Section 1. BASIC DOCUMENTS: Program Action Forms Accepted Proposals Tax Forms an d Certifications Docket Excerpts Request for Grant Action (RGA) Grant Notification Letter & Budget Terms of Grant Grant Acceptance Letter Supplementary Requests & Agreements Modification Requests & Agreements Section 2. PAYMENTS: Requests Letters Acknowledgments Section 3. REPORTS: Grant Status Report Forms Grantee Narrative and Financial Reports Section 4. CORRESPONDENCE: All other correspondence and material, in reverse chronological order
A possible 5th section, 'ATTACHMENTS', will contain copies of printed ephemera & clippings related to the grant. Grant Files may also be followed by a 'Grants Accounting File' which summarizes the grant.
Also, early Grant Files (roughly 1950-1970) often include a CROSS REFERENCE sheet listing other grants made in a related subject or Program Area, and a 'BIBLIOGRAPHY of GRANT-RELATED MATERIALS' at the beginning of the file.
Conditions Governing Access
Grants inactive for more than 10 years are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Grant administration files
- Ford Foundation Grants - Them to Tw, 1937-2006
  - The Mace Fund (08500337), 1984 (Reel R7373, Reel R7374)
    Grant Purpose
    FUNDING FOR TIE-OFF (ENDOWMENT) SUPPORT
    Program Name
    Urban Poverty Program [UP]
    Grant Amount
    $2,800,000.00;$2,800,000.00
    Program Officer
    Anglin, Roland
    Mississippi
  - The Madame Walker Building Urban Life Center, Inc. (09601298), 1996 September 01-1998 August 31 (Reel R8502)
    SUPPORT TO IMPLEMENT PROGRAMS THAT SPONSOR U.S.-BASED COLLABORATIONS WITH PERFORMING ARTISTS OF AFRICA
    Education & Culture Program [EC]
    $200,000.00;$200,000.00
    Vincent, Christine J.
    United States
  - The Madame Walker Building Urban Life Center, Inc. (09800814), 1998 June 01-2001 May 31 (Reel R8525)
    SUPPORT TO BEGIN INSTITUTIONALIZING MULTI-PARTNER PROGRAMS THAT SPONSOR U.S.-BASED COLLABORATIONS WITH PERFORMING ARTISTS OF AFRICA (960-1298)
    Media Arts and Culture
    $100,000.00;$100,000.00
    United States; Performing Arts--Africa
  - The Maharashtra Association for the Cultivation of Science (08150408), 1981 March 12-1984 March 31 (Reel R5026)
    SUPPORT SEMINAR ON NUTRITION PLANNING
    India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi)
    $13,500.00;$13,500.00
    Chen, Lincoln C.
    India
  - The Maharashtra Association for the Cultivation of Science (08450452), 1983 December 01-1985 November 30 (Reel R5251)
    SUPPORT FOR THE CONSULTANT SERVICES OF PROFESSOR SHELDON MARGEN IN THE TEACHING AND RESEARCH PROGRAM OF THE ASSOCIATION (INDIA)
    $6,000.00;$3,151.00
  - The Maharashtra Association for the Cultivation of Science (08750482), 1987 March 25-1990 March 31 (Reel R6348)
    SERVICES OF VISITING PROFESSORS IN THE RESEARCH AND TEACHING PROGRAM OF THE ASSOCIATION
    $10,000.00;$8,785.68
    Pachauri, Saroj
  - The Mahatma Gandhi Memorial College Trust, Udupi (08201011), 1983 February 09-1995 August 31 (Reel R6768)
    SUPPORT FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF PERFORMING FOLK ARTS IN INDIA
    $263,500.00;$263,500.00
    Vellani, Anmo l.
  - The Mahatma Gandhi Memorial College Trust, Udupi (09000628), 1990 April 24-2000 May 29 (Reel R8572)
    ENDOWMENT SUPPORT FOR THE REGIONAL RESOURCES CENTRE
    $150,000.00;$150,000.00
    Ramanathan, Sharada
  - The Mahatma Gandhi Memorial College Trust, Udupi (09401251), 1994 November 10-2003 April 23 (Reel R8988)
    SUPPORT FOR A PROGRAM OF DOCUMENTATION, RESEARCH, ARCHIVING, NETWORKING AND COMMUNITY OUTREACH IN INDIAN FOLKLORE
    $165,000.00;$165,000.00
  - The Mahatma Gandhi Memorial College Trust, Udupi (09500749), 1995 May 30-2000 May 31 (Reel R8609)
    SUPPORT FOR PURCHASE OF EQUIPMENT AND RAW STOCK
    $65,000.00;$65,000.00
  - The Manchester Citizens Corporation (08300640), 1983 July 01-1985 June 30 (Reel R6415)
    TO ASSIST IN ESTABLISHMENT OF MANCHESTER DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION AND ITS FIRST MAJOR HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROJECT
    $101,000.00;$101,000.00
    Howard, Craig
    Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - The Manhattan Country School (07100399), 1971 June 01-1972 August 31 (Reel R1835)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR THE EXPLORATION OF A NEW TUITION SYSTEM BASE ON "ABILITY TO PAY"
    Education and Public Policy
    $30,295.00;$30,295.00
    Kelly, James A.
    New York (State)
  - The Manhattan Country School (07550124), 1974 December 11-1981 July 14 (Reel R2987)
    SUPPORT TO PREPARE AND PUBLISH PUBLIC REPORTS REGARDING THE SCHOOL'S UNIQUE VARIABLE TUITION SCHEME
    $15,045.00;$15,045.00
    Meade, Edward J.
  - The Maniben and Mohamedally Rattansi Educational Trust (10051785), 2000 September 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9178)
    Support for planning activities to increase the organization's endowment and development effective grantmaking and governance systems
    Eastern Africa (Nairobi)
    $70,000.00;$70,000.00
    Akin Aina, Tade
    Kenya; Humanitarianism--Kenya
  - The Mannes College Of Music (06400058), 1964 January 01-1971 June 30 (Reel R2070)
    SCHOLARSHIP AID TO TALENTED STUDENTS IN PROFESSIONAL TRAINING IN CREATIVE MUSIC
    Office Of Vice President -Finance & Administration
    $40,000.00;$40,000.00
    Thompson, Marcia T.
  - The Mannes College Of Music (07600494), 1976 July 01-1981 June 30 (Reel R2871)
    SUPPORT OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE MANNES COLLEGE ORCHESTRA PROGRAM
  - The Maple Women's Psychological Counseling Center (10100585), 2001 March 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9217)
    Support for a Chinese nongovernmental organization to provide legal and psychological services for women
    China (Beijing)
    $230,300.00;$230,300.00
    Liu, Mina;Kaufman, Joan
    China; Women--China--Services for; Legal assistance to women--China; Mental health counseling--China
  - The Mar Vista Institute (09701814), 1997 September 01-2000 October 31 (Reel R8525)
    CORE SUPPORT
    Human Development and Reproductive Health
    $750,000.00;$750,000.00
    Neuborne, Helen;Floyd, Virginia Davis
  - The Mare Center for Solidary Action and Study (10351332), 2003 July 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9073)
    To create a network of current and former university students residing in the favelas that comprise Rio de Janeiro's Mare Complex and train them in applied research and public policy analysis
    Brazil (Rio de Janeiro)
    $30,000.00;$30,000.00
    Leeds, Elizabeth R.
    Brazil
  - The Marion County (Kansas) Welfare Department (06000356), 1960 July 20-1963 July 19 (Reel R1543)
    COMMUNITY DEMONSTRATION PROJECT TO IMPROVE PRIVATE AND PUBLIC PROGRAMS FOR OLDER PEOPLE
    $26,500.00;$26,500.00
    Bischoff, Irma E.
  - The Marshall Foundation, Incorporated (06300542), 1963 September 26-1964 September 25 (Reel R0270)
    STRENGTHENING OF A PROGRAM OF TEACHER EDUCATION AT MARSHALL UNIVERSITY
    $25,000.00;$25,000.00
    Fantini, Mario D.
  - The Martha Graham School Of Contemporary Dance, Inc. (06500360), 1965 September 23-1965 September 22 (Reel R0948)
    USE OF A RECORDING IN THE CREATION AND REHEARSAL OF A NEW REPERTORY WORK IN THE DANCE
    $6,000.00;$6,000.00
  - The Martin Luther King,jr.Center For Nonviolent Social Change,inc. (07000089), 1969 December 04-1970 December 03 (Reel R1654)
    SUPPORT OF AFRO-AMERICAN STUDIES PROGRAM
    Cook, Sarah
  - The Martin Luther King,jr.Center For Nonviolent Social Change,inc. (07100323), 1971 May 13-1973 May 12 (Reel R1726)
    GENERAL SUPPORT FOR THE CENTER'S LIBRARY-DOCUMENTATION PROJECT
    National Affairs [NA]
    George, Bryant
  - The Martin Luther King,jr.Center For Nonviolent Social Change,inc. (07400549), 1974 July 01-1975 June 30 (Reel R1260)
    FACILITATE PLANNING AND FINANCING EFFORTS OF THE CENTER
    National Affairs [NA];Education and Public Policy
    George, Bryant;Payton, Benjamin Franklin
    United States; Atlanta (Ga.)
  - The Martin Luther King,jr.Center for Nonviolent Social Change,inc. (08450669), 1984 August 01-1986 July 31 (Reel R4511)
    SUPPORT FOR FUNDRAISING ENHANCEMENT EFFORTS THROUGH EXPANSION OF THE DEVELOPMENT OFFICE
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]
    $50,000.00;$50,000.00
    Huntley, Lynn
  - The Maryland Committee For The Humanities, Inc. (07900335), 1979 April 01-1980 March 31 (Reel R2601)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT OF A FILM BY MICHAEL LAWRENCE ON THE NATURE OF THEMUSICAL EXPERIENCE
    Office Of The Arts
    $28,680.00;$28,680.00
    Sarraf, Laurice H.;Sheldon, Richard C.
    Maryland
  - The Maryland Institute (06400059), 1964 January 01-1971 June 30 (Reel R2070)
    SCHOLARSHIP AID TO TALENTED STUDENTS IN PROFESSIONAL TRAINING IN FINE ARTS
  - The Maryland Institute (07450775), 1974 July 01-1981 June 30 (Reel R2538, Reel R2539)
    SUPPORT OF PROFESSIONAL STUDIO TRAINING IN THE VISUAL ARTS
    $600,000.00;$600,000.00
    Sarraf, Laurice H.
  - The Maryland Legal Services Corporation (08650454), 1986 May 14-1987 May 14 (Reel R5617)
    SUPPORT FOR A CONFERENCE TO EXPLORE THE CREATION OF A NATIONAL IOLTA DIRECTORS ASSOCIATION
    $15,000.00;$15,000.00
    McClymont, Mary (Mary E.)
  - The Massachusetts General Hospital (05600229), 1956 (Reel R2387)
    RESEARCH IN MENTAL HEALTH
    Special Programs
    $250,000.00;$250,000.00
    Nims, William H.
  - The Massachusetts General Hospital (06100293), 1961 August 02-1964 August 01 (Reel R1013)
    GENERAL PROGRAM OF THE DEPARTMENT OF MEDICINE AND RADIOLOGY
  - The Math/science Network (08850553), 1988 July 01-1989 August 30 (Reel R6233)
    DEV'T OF A PILOT PROGRAM TO MAKE THE NETWORK'S NATIONAL CONFERENCE PROGRAM ON CAREERS IN MATHEMATICS MORE RELEVANT TO MINORITY GIRLS
    $57,200.00;$57,200.00
    Nelson, Barbara S.
  - The Mathematical Association Of America, Inc. (05500061), 1955 March 29-1963 January 01 (Reel R0190)
    STATUS OF TEACHING, RESEARCH AND USE OF MATHEMATICS, AND RELATIONSHIPS OF SCIENCES AND OTHER FIELDS OF KNOWLEDGE
    $175,000.00;$175,000.00
  - The Mathematical Association of America, Inc. (08751058), 1988 January 01-1990 December 31 (Reel R6194)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF A NATIONAL NETWORK FOR LOCALLY ORGANIZED MATHEMATICS TEACHER PROJECTS
  - The Mathematical Association of America, Inc. (08850525), 1988 April 01-1989 March 31 (Reel R5788)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT OF A TASK FORCE ON MINORITIES IN MATHEMATICS
  - The Mba-Nonprofit Connection (09850304), 1997 October 01-1998 October 31 (Reel R7974)
    MEETING OF BUSINESS SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS & FACULTY ABOUT CORPORATE SOCIAL RESPONSIBILITY, PUBLIC SERVICE & NONPROFIT MANAGEMENT
    Economic Development
    $10,500.00;$10,500.00
    Kahane, Michele F.
    United States; Social responsibility of business
  - The Mboza Trust (10051310), 2000 May 01-2002 April 30 (Reel R8953)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT TO THE LUBOMBO WATERWAYS PROGRAM FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF A PROGRAM OF RESOURCE USE PLANNING, TRAINING AND TECHNICAL SUPPORT FOR COMMUNITIES IN THE PONGOLA AND RIO MAPUTO FLOODPLAINS
    Southern Africa (Johannesburg)
    Murombedzi, James C.
    Mozambique; South Africa; Watershed management--South Africa; Rivers--South Africa--Regulation
  - The Media Institute (09900857), 1999 May 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8899)
    RESEARCH ON MEDIA LAWS IN KENYA
    $75,000.00;$75,000.00
    Gitari, Joseph
    Africa, East; Mass media--Law and legislation--Research--Africa, Eastern; Civil society -- Kenya -- Citizen participation
  - The Mediae Trust (10051781), 2000 July 01-2001 June 30 (Reel R8924)
    SUPPORT FOR AN ASSESSMENT OF THE ROLE AND POTENTIAL OF PERFORMING ARTS AND MEDIA IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF CREATIVE EXPRESSION IN EAST AFRICA
    $99,000.00;$99,000.00
    Burnet, J. Robert
    Africa, East; Creative ability -- Africa, Eastern; Arts -- Africa, Eastern; Mass media--Africa, Eastern
  - The Mediae Trust (10151768), 2001 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8912)
    For planning, design and launch of a new music support organization in Kenya
    Kenya; Musicians--Services for--Kenya; Human rights; Arts and society -- Kenya; Civil society -- Kenya
  - The Mediae Trust (10350750), 2003 April 01-2005 March 31 (Reel R9180)
    To document indigenous medicinal knowledge in five Kenyan communities
    Burris, Mary Ann
    Kenya
  - The Medical Association of Tanzania (09550638), 1995 February 01-1996 January 30 (Reel R7044)
    NATIONAL WORKSHOP ON MEDICAL ETHICS AND HUMAN RIGHTS
    $38,500.00;$38,500.00
    Bangser, Maggie A.;Garling, Marguerite L.
    Tanzania
  - The Medical Association of Tanzania (09750616), 1997 March 01-1998 February 28 (Reel R7486)
    WORKSHOP TO DEVELOP A TRAINING MANUAL ON MEDICAL ETHICS AND HUMAN RIGHTS
    $14,000.00;$14,000.00
  - The Medical College Of Pennsylvania (07450276), 1974 February 01-1974 June 30 (Reel R1502)
    SUPPORT FOR AN ACTION PLANNING WORKSHOP BY THE CENTER FOR WOMEN IN MEDICINE
    $10,757.00;$10,757.00
    Chamberlain, Mariam
  - The Medical College Of St. Bartholomew'S Hospital (07800351), 1978 January 01-1979 June 30 (Reel R4698)
    SUPPORT FOR RESEARCH ON QUALITATIVE CHANGES IN PEPTIDES SECRETED BY RHESUS MONKEY PITUITARY AND HYPOTHALAMUS DURING FETAL DEVELOP
    Population [POP]
    $49,000.00;$49,000.00
    Atkinson, Linda E.
    Global
  - The Medical Research Council (06600462), 1966 October 06-1971 October 05 (Reel R1184)
    STUDY OF GONADOTROPHIC HORMONES AND FERTILITY CONTROL
    $265,000.00;$265,000.00
    Southam, Anna L.
  - The Memphis Academy Of Arts (06400060), 1964 January 01-1971 June 30 (Reel R2070)
    $20,000.00;$20,000.00
  - The Memphis Academy Of Arts (07450777), 1974 July 01-1981 June 30 (Reel R2390)
    $826,500.00;$826,500.00
    Tennessee
  - The Memphis City Schools (08100929), 1981 October 01-1985 December 31 (Reel R4922)
    SUPPORT FOR PROJECTS IN MEMPHIS TO IMPROVE TEACHING AND LEARNING IN URBAN SCHOOLS
    $629,526.00;$629,526.00
    Memphis (Tenn.)
  - The Memphis City Schools (08251158), 1982 October 15-1983 October 14 (Reel R4588)
    CITY HIGH SCHOOL RECOGNITION PROGRAM GRANT FOR CARVER HIGH SCHOOL FOR SCHOOL IMPROVEMENT ACTIVITIES
  - The Memphis City Schools (08700040), 1986 October 01-1987 November 30 (Reel R5604)
    SUPPORT TO ASSIST A SCHOOL AND COMMUNITY COLLABORATIVE TO DEVELOP PLANS AND PROGRAMS TO PREVENT SCH0OL DROPOUTS
  - The Memphis City Schools (08800247), 1988 January 01-1990 June 01 (Reel R6214)
    SUPPORT TO DIRECTLY AND INDIRECTLY ASSIST SCHOOL COMMUNITY COLLABORATIVES IMPLEMENT PLANS TO PREVENT SCHOOL DROPOUTS
    $90,000.00;$90,000.00
  - The Memphis-Plough Community Foundation (08700138), 1987 January 01-1991 December 31 (Reel R6245)
    LEADERSHIP PROGRAM FOR COMMUNITY FOUNDATIONS CHALLENGE GRANT FOR AN ADOLESCENT PREGNANCY PREVENTION PROGRAM AND ASSET BUILDING(CFI)
    US & International Affairs Programs - Office Of Vice President [USIAP/OVP]
    $500,000.00;$500,000.00
    Brown, Prudence
  - The Mendenhall Ministries, Inc. (08450949), 1984 September 29-1986 August 31 (Reel R4791)
    SUPPORT OF CHURCH-SPONSORED LEGAL SERVICES AND EDUCATIONAL OUTREACH ACTIVITIES TO THE BLACK RURAL POOR
  - The Mendenhall Ministries, Inc. (08600763), 1986 August 05-1998 June 30 (Reel R8011, Reel R8119)
    SUPPORT OF CHURCH-BASED LEGAL SERVICES AND LEADERSHIP DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMS
    $1,505,214.00;$1,505,214.00
    Davie, Fred A.
    United States; Mississippi
  - The Mendenhall Ministries, Inc. (09551399), 1995 September 01-1996 August 31 (Reel R7418)
    SUPPORT TO AUGMENT THE ORGANIZATION'S RESERVE FUND
  - The Menninger Foundation (05600230), 1956 July 18-1968 December 31 (Reel R2387)
    $350,000.00;$350,000.00
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (04100254), 1941 (Reel R1192)
    GENERAL SUPPORT OF EDUCATIONAL ACTIVITIES
    $2,500.00;$2,500.00
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (05200081), 1952 (Reel R1192)
    EDUCATIONAL ACTIVITIES - GENERAL SUPPORT
    $300,000.00;$300,000.00
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (05600011), 1955 December 08-1960 December 07 (Reel R1192)
    GENERAL SUPPORT OF PROGRAM
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (06400223), 1964 March 27-1967 March 26 (Reel R2313)
    GENERAL SUPPORT
    $60,000.00;$60,000.00
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (07500447), 1975 July 01-1977 August 31 (Reel R2340, Reel R2341)
    PLAN AND IMPLEMENT RESEARCH AND PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT ACTIVITIES RELATED TO EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION & FAMILY SEX ROLES
    Kelly, James A.;Saario, Terry
    New Mexico
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (07650253), 1976 February 23-1977 September 01 (Reel R1392)
    EDITING OF THE MANUSCRIPT RESULTING FROM THE WORKING CONFERENCE ON FAMILY AND SEX ROLES
    $3,000.00;$3,000.00
    Saario, Terry
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (07800228), 1978 February 15-1980 February 14 (Reel R2327)
    GENERAL SUPPORT OF THE INSTITUTE'S ACTIVITIES
    Kelly, James A.;Lynch, Barbara D.
    Michigan
  - The Merrill-Palmer Institute (07800372), 1978 April 17-1980 June 30 (Reel R2964)
    SUPPORT OF THE CHILD CARE SUB-STUDY
    $227,505.00;$227,505.00
    Berresford, Susan V. (Susan Vail)
    Detroit (Mich.)
  - The Methodist Church in Kenya (08850371), 1988 February 04-1989 August 03 (Reel R5799)
    SUPPORT FOR A FAMILY LIFE EDUCATION PROGRAM FOR ADOLESCENTS USING FAMILY AND COMMUNITY-BASED COMMUNICATION IN MERU, KENYA
    $44,900.00;$44,900.00
    Saint, William S.
  - The Methodist Church in Kenya (09000631), 1990 April 19-1995 November 30 (Reel R8043)
    SUPPORT FOR RESEARCH AND DISSEMINATION OF AN INFORMATION-EDUCATION PROGRAM FOR ADOLESCENTS IN KENYA
    $42,500.00;$42,500.00
  - The Metropolitan Human Relations Commission (08050501), 1980 May 15-1983 September 30 (Reel R4154, Reel R5157)
    SUPPORT FOR A PROGRAM TO COMBAT DISCRIMINATION IN HOUSING
    $25,000.00;$21,457.03
  - The Metropolitan Museum Of Art (06300094), 1963 January 09-1972 June 30 (Reel R2637, Reel R2668)
    PREP. & PUBLICATION OF SCHOLARLY CATALOGUES OF THE MUSEUM'S COLLEC. & PREP OF 2-VOL CATALOGUE OF 19TH-CEN. AMER. PAINTINGS
    $33,525.00;$33,525.00
  - The Metropolitan Museum of Art (08550941), 1985 September 16-1986 January 15 (Reel R5397)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR PUBLICATION OF THE "INDIA!" EXHIBITION CATALOG
    Education & Culture Program [EC];India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (New Delhi)
    Mayleas, Ruth R.;Vellani, Anmo l.
    India; United States
  - The Metropolitan Museum of Art (10050240), 1999 December 01-2000 November 30 (Reel R8607)
    TO SUPPORT AN EXHIBITION CATALOGUE AND WEB-BASED RESOURCES IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE MUSEUM PLANNED EXHIBITION, ART AND ORACLE: AFRICAN ART AND THE RITUALS OF DIVINATION.
    Pwono, Damien M.;Vincent, Christine J.
    United States; African art -- Exhibitions; African art -- Religious aspects
  - The Metropolitan Museum of Art (10351158), 2003 April 01-2003 September 30 (Reel R8997)
    For a one-day interdisciplinary symposium to accompany the exhibit Genesis: Ideas of Origin in African Sculpture
    Pwono, Damien M.
  - The Metropolitan Youth Development Council (06400126), 1964 January 07-1967 March 31 (Reel R2095)
    COMMUNITY ACTION AND RESEARCH PROJECT ON YOUTH EMPLOYMENT AND DELINQUENCY
    $91,000.00;$91,000.00
  - The Mexican Museum (08900644), 1989 May 01-1991 December 31 (Reel R6264)
    SUPPORT FOR BLACK AND HISPANIC ART MUSEUMS (002)
    Mayleas, Ruth R.
    Puerto Rico; United States
  - The Mexican Museum (09001121), 1990 August 01-1992 June 30 (Reel R6267)
    United States; San Francisco (Calif.)
  - The Mexican Museum (09101053), 1991 August 01-1994 June 30 (Reel R6396)
    Mayleas, Ruth R.;Vincent, Christine J.
  - The Mexican Museum (09301488), 1993 September 01-1995 August 31 (Reel R6879)
    SUPPORT FOR AFRICAN AMERICAN AND LATINO ART MUSEUMS (002)
    $190,000.00;$190,000.00
  - The Mexican Network of Campesino Forestry Organizations (09700772), 1997 March 01-2001 February 28 (Reel R8912)
    SUPPORT FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF EXPANDED COMMUNITY-BASED FORESTRY MANAGEMENT IN MEXICO
    Mexico and Central America (Mexico City)
    $270,000.00;$270,000.00
    Barry, Deborah
    Mexico
  - The Michigan Community Coordinated Child Care Association (09000232), 1990 January 01-1993 September 30 (Reel R6500, Reel R6501)
    PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR THE REPLICATION OF THE CALIFORNIA CHILD CARE INITIATIVE IN MICHIGAN
    $400,000.00;$400,000.00
    Miller, Shelby H.;Molnar, Janice M.
    United States; Michigan
  - The Michigan Council For The Humanities (07950188), 1979 January 01-1979 March 31 (Reel R3669)
    SUPPORT FOR DISTRIBUTION OF THE FILM "WITH BABIES AND BANNERS"
    $10,000.00;$10,000.00
  - The Microcapital Institute (10251431), 2002 July 01-2003 April 30 (Reel R9154)
    To develop, pilot and disseminate a quantitative tool to measure the social benefits of investment in microfinance
    Myhre, David
  - The Middle East Institute (05200161), 1952 (Reel R0699)
    SUPPORT OF .THE MIDDLE-EAST JOURNAL.
    Africa & The Middle East [AME]
  - The Middle East Institute (05400136), 1954 September 17-1957 September 16 (Reel R0425)
    PERIODIC SURVEY AND REPORT ON RESEARCH ON NEAR AND MIDDLE EAST AND AFRICA NORTH OF THE SAHARA
    $27,950.00;$27,950.00
  - The Middle East Institute (05500220), 1955 October 20-1965 December 07 (Reel R0700)
    SUPPORT FOR MIDDLE EAST JOURNAL
  - The Middle East Institute (05600285), 1956 July 30-1957 January 29 (Reel R0291)
    SUPPORT OF STUDY OF ROLE OF WOMEN IN THE MOSLEM EAST
    $18,000.00;$18,000.00
  - The Middle East Institute (05700125), 1957 March 05-1959 October 29 (Reel R0783)
    DEVELOPMENT AND INTRODUCTION OF UNIFIED ARABIC ALPHABET IN THE NEAR EAST
    $137,800.00;$137,800.00
  - The Middle East Institute (07300158), 1973 January 30-1974 January 29 (Reel R1230)
    SUPPORT FOR AN ARAB-WESTERN DIALOGUE
    $39,300.00;$37,760.17
    Robarts, Richard C.
    Middle East; Africa, North